In this video we're going to look at the error surface for a linear neuron.
这个视频，我们将会讨论线性神经元的误差曲面。
By understanding the shape of this error surface, we can understand a lot about
理解了误差曲面的形状， 我们就会对
what happens as a linear neuron is learning.
线性神经元的学习过程中所发生的事情了解的更多。
We can get a nice geometrical understanding of what's happening when we
在训练线性神经元的权重时， 我们可以对所发生的事情有一个很好的几何学理解。
learn the weights of a linear neuron. By considering a space that's very like
我们可以假设一个
the weight space that we use to understand perceptrons, but it has one extra
类似于之前理解感知器时所用的空间
dimension. So we imagine a space in which all the
但是多了一个维度。 现在假设一个空间，
horizontal dimensions correspond to the weights.
其所有水平的维度都是权重，
And there's one vertical dimension that corresponds to the error.
此外还有一个垂直的维度，代表着误差。
So in this space, points on the horizontal plane, correspond to different settings of
在这个空间里， 水平平面上的点代表不同的权重集合。
the weights. And the height corresponds to the error
高度代表相应权重上，
that your making with that set of weights, summed over all training cases.
所有训练数据错误的加和。
For a linear neuron, the errors you make for each set of weights define error
对线性神经元而言， 每组权重的集合对于的错误组成了误差曲面。
surface. And this error surface is a quadratic
这个曲面是个二次的碗状。
bowl. That is, if you take a vertical
如果垂直切开，
cross-section, it's always a parabola. And if you take a horizontal
你总能得到一个抛物线。 如果水平切开，总是一个椭圆形。
cross-section, it's always an ellipse. This is only true for linear systems with
这仅仅适用于平方误差。
a squared error. As soon as we go to a multilayer nonlinear
当我们开始讨论多层，非线性神经网络时，
neuron nets, this error surface will get more complicated.
误差曲面会变得更加复杂。
As long as the weights aren't too big, the error surface will still be smooth, but it
当参数还不是很多的时候， 误差曲面还会是光滑的，
may have many local minimum. Using this error surface we can get a
但可能存在局部最优。 使用上述误差曲面，
picture of what's happening as we do gradient descent learning using the delta
我们可以得到当我们使用 德尔塔定律来进行梯度下降学习时的场景。
rule. So what the delta rule does is it computes
德尔塔定律，
the derivative of the error with respect to the weights.
计算了误差相对于参数的导数。
And if you change the weights in proportion to that derivative, that's
我们相当于在误差曲面进行最急速的下降。
equivalent to doing steepest descent on the error surface.
当我们使用得到的导数来改变权重时，
To put it another way, if we look at the error surface from above, we get
换个方式理解， 当我们从上方来观察误差曲线时，
elliptical contour lines. And the delta rule is gonna take it at
我们会看到椭圆的轮廓线。
right angles to those elliptical contour lines, as shown in the picture.
德尔塔定律，如上图， 在椭圆轮廓线上指明了正确的方向。
That's what happens with what's called batch learning, where we get the grayed
其发生在批量学习的场景， 在这个场景，梯度是在所有的训练样本上加和得到的。
in, summed overall training cases. But we could also do online learning,
此外，我们也进行在线学习，
where after each training case, we change the weights in proportion to the gradient
对于每个训练样本， 我们都会依照这个样本上计算出来的梯度来修改权重。
for that single training case. That's much more like what we do in
这和我们在感知器学习中所做的类似。
perceptrons. And, as you can see, the change in the
你可以看到， 权重的调整使我们
weights moves us towards one of these constraint planes.
向一个其中一个控制面移动。
So in the picture on the right, there are two training cases.
在右图中， 有两个训练样本。
To get the first training case correct, we must lie on one of those blue lines.
要让第一个样本正确， 我们必须在其中一条蓝线上，
And to get the second training case correct, the two weights must lie on the
要让第二个样本正确，我们必须在另一条蓝线上。
other blue line. So if we start at one of those red points,
因为，我们从其中一个红点开始，
and we compute the gradient on the first training case, the delta rule will move us
然后我们开始计算第一个样本的梯度， 德尔塔定律
perpendicularly towards that line. If we then consider the other training
会让我们垂直的奔向那条线。 当我们考虑另一个样本的时候，
case, we'll move perpendicularly towards the other line.
我们则垂直的奔向另一条线。
And if we alternate between the two training cases, we'll zigzag backwards and
当我们在两个样本间不停交换时，
forwards, moving towards the solution point which is where those two lines
我们呈锯齿状移动，直至最终解， 即最终两条线的交点。
intersect. That's the set of weights that is correct
这一点上的权重参数可以同时满足两个样本。
for both training cases. Using this picture of the error surface,
使用误差曲面，
we can also understand the conditions it will make learning very slow.
我们也能理解何种条件可以让训练很慢。
If that ellipse is very elongated, which is gonna happen if the lines that
如果训练样本对应的先几乎平行， 那么误差曲面的椭圆会很扁，
correspond to training cases is almost parallel, then when we look at the
当我们观察梯度时，
gradient, it's going to have a nasty property.
其有个不好的属性。
If you look at the red arrow in the picture, the gradient is big in the
请看图中红色的箭头， 梯度在我们不想移动太多的方向很大，
direction in which we don't want to move very far, and it's small in the direction
但在我们需要移动很长的方向则很小。
in which we want to move a long way. So the gradient will quickly take us
所以梯度很快带领我们越过谷底，
across the bottom of that ravine. Corresponding to the narrow axis of the
即椭圆的短轴。
ellipse. And will take a long time to take us along
我们要很长的时间，
the ravine, corresponding to the long Xs of the ellipse.
才能沿着峡谷即椭圆的长轴前进。
It's just the opposite of what we want. We'd like to get a great into a small
这不是我们想要的。 我们想得到一个梯度，在越过峡谷方向前进一点点，
across the ravine, and big along the ravine but that's not what we get.
沿着峡谷方向一大步，但是我们得到不是这个。
And so, simple steepest descent, in which you change each weight in proportion to a
所以，简单的最快梯度下降， 每次使用学习率乘以误差的导数来调整参数权重，
learning rate times the error derivative, is gonna have great difficulty, with very
在图示中这种很扁的
elongated surfaces like the one shown in the picture.
误差曲面的情况下会遇到极大的困难。